<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my site on trevor mckay</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my site on trevor mckay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 Trevor McKay</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 20:59:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>_fzf-open_: a fuzzy file search with a sensible opener</title>
      <link>/posts/fzf_opener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 20:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fzf_opener/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/fzf_open_demo.gif&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          Just like macOS Spotlight, but different!
One of my most sorely missed features from macOS was the Spotlight search. It can be incredibly helpful to open the search, type a few characters, and be viewing/editing the file I want within just moments.
This, unfortunately, does not exist in Linux outside of similar features integrated in desktop environments such as Gnome. What to do if your favorite DE does not have such a feature or you only have a window manager?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Hello, my name is Trevor. I am a student pursuing a degree in Computer Engineering with a minor in German Language and Culture. I like hardware design and FPGAs, RISC-V, embedded, and Linux. I also like the outdoors, cycling and volleyball!
I am currently looking for work! Here is some of my relevent experience and skills, at a glance. Of course, you can always just email me if you&amp;rsquo;d rather have my resume.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated backups with _rsync_, _anacron_, and the cloud</title>
      <link>/posts/rsync-anacron-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rsync-anacron-backups/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Anyone using Linux as their daily driver knows how devastating it can be to lose all your personal and configuration files to hardware failure. As such, most users have some way to keep their files safe. Many choose to use some sort of dotfile management system. This is is a great choice as it allows for version control and branches for multiple machines. However, dotfiles are not the only thing you want to preserve.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>