<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Trevor McKay</title>
    <link>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Trevor McKay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Trevor McKay</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.trmckay.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with baremetal Rust on RISC-V</title>
      <link>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/riscv-baremetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/riscv-baremetal/</guid>
      <description>I have been experimenting with Rust lately and it has been really fun. One of my recent challenges to myself was to see if I could get baremetal Rust running on my pretty barebones RISC-V chip. It&amp;rsquo;s rv32i with a very limited amount of space and sort-of weird memory map. This sort of thing is trivial to deal with when writing assembly, and still not too bad when writing C. However, step further away from the metal, and your very precise target becomes harder and harder to hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises in assembly: recursion</title>
      <link>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/fib_asm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 18:48:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/fib_asm/</guid>
      <description>Trying to implement a recursive algorithm in assembly is both a challenging puzzle and very informative exercise to demonstrate some important properties of recursion and function calls in general.
Recursion Recursion is super important for writing clean and concise solutions to a whole subset of programming tasks. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say it&amp;rsquo;s without its drawbacks.
Some problems can be solved both iteratively and recursively. Due to the way a computer works—specifically the stack—the recursive solution often produces less efficient code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate backups with rsync</title>
      <link>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/rsync-anacron-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:22:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.trmckay.com/posts/rsync-anacron-backups/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows how devastating it can be to lose all your personal and configuration files to hardware failure. As such, most users have some way to keep their files safe. Many choose to use some sort of dotfile management system. This is is a great choice as it allows for version control and branches for multiple machines. However, dotfiles are not the only thing you want to preserve. Furthermore, when it comes to backups, more redundancy is never a bad thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
